Visiting a documentation site for any
language
or framework can be a little bit daunting.
But the truth is, is that you don't need
to understand all of it.
We'll be hanging out in several sections
of the jQuery documentation, during the
jQuery basics.
These sections will cover the following
components of the jQuery API.
So there's one set of methods that deal
with manipulation and that means changing
the DOM.
So you can change the HTML elements on
a DOM by either adding them or removing
them.
You can update or read the attributes on
an HTML element.
And finally you can hide or show elements
or cause some
sort of light transformation effects to
happen and that's manipulation over time.
Another set of methods deal with
Traversing, that
means moving around the DOM from element
to element.
How that could mean a parent element to
it's
children all or from the child to the
parent elements.
Or sibling to sibling elements, which
means these elements have a common parent.
And the final set of methods we're gonna
look at are event methods.
So these tend to deal with keyboard events
or mouse events.
A keyboard event would be a keypress.
A mouse event could be its movement or its
clicks.
So, from the jquery.com website, you can
click on the
API documentation to have a look at what
you can do.
Now ,on the left hand side it can be a
little
bit daunting because there is lots and
lots of sub-categories here.
And a lot of these you won't even use.
So I'm gonna go over some of these and
categorize them
for you see a kind of can get a feel of
what
kind of things you can do and where you
can look
up in your own time when you need to
develop using jQuery.
So here we are in the Attributes category.
Now the Attributes category has a list of
methods
that you can use to modify the attributes
of elements.
So, an example of an Attribute say on an
anchor or a link would be the href
attribute.
So the href [INAUDIBLE] attribute has the
URL of the link that you wanna go to.
Say that you wanted to get that or even
modify that,
you can use some of these methods here to
do that.
So attributes also includes classes as
well so you can add and remove classes.
You can check whether if a element has a
class.
And you can come here to the attributes
and
take a look and use some of the methods
here.
Over in the CSS category, this is really
very specific to the CSS of an element.
You can change style properties at will,
you could read style properties at
will, and you can do the same things like
add classes and remove.
Some of these methods are duplicated
throughout different categories
but this once again is a manipulation type
of category.
Now Dimensions is handy because you can
check the dimensions of a
given element, you can figure out its
height, width or height and width
without its Paddings and borders and
things like that, and that can be handy
to interrogate when you're doing some
custom animations, or things like that.
Now, dimensions is technically
manipulation, because you're
getting the information of a given thing.
You're not tra, traversing or doing any
event-based stuff.
So, this can be handy to figure out the
dimensions of a particular element.
The next category I wanna take a look at
is Effects.
Now effects is basically manipulation over
time.
You're doing an animation that may last
several seconds, or you may be
showing, hiding, fading in, fading out,
sliding things in and out.
This all happens over time, so effects is
manipulation over time.
Now the next category I want to look at is
Events.
Now, before I click through I'll just want
to
have a look at these various different
sub-categories here.
So, an event is basically when a user
interacts with a thing.
So a user may interact with the keyboard
in a form
using a mouse or scrolling in a browser or
re-sizing a browser window.
Also there are special events that are
triggered by the browser itself when
something happens.
So, these are events that are triggered
and
then you can do something when that event
occurs.
So that's the kind of things that you need
to keep in mind with events.
They can be user-triggered or by the
computer itself it can trigger an event.
So, so if we click on the category of
events, we can see
a list of all the kinds of events that you
want to do.
Now this isn't very good to look at
necessarily because it includes all
the events, so you may want to focus in on
a sub-category of events.
Say if you know that you want to deal with
a mouse movement or something like that.
You would look in here.
So these events are often duplicated in
the parent event
category so sometimes it's best to look at
the various small
sections of the documentation that you
wanna look at so if
you want to look at the mass events just
do that.
Now we're gonna take a look at Offset.
Now Offset is very similar to the
Dimensions, is
to figure out the offsets of a particular
element.
So, whether if it's from the top of the
left of a parent element or
they, the document as a whole how far it
scrolls like up or left.
These are all handy if you want to trigger
an event for the browser to scroll
back up to the top of a page or down to a
page, things like that.
So, that's the kind of thing that you want
to do here, this is manipulation again.
You can query the offset.
And you can actually animate the offset in
some circumstances.
Finally, Traversing.
Now, Traversing includes all the methods
that you want to do to actually
move around the document and manipulate
things while you're traversing.
So, if you wanted to get the children of
an element or the
closest element with a given CSS light so
you can do things like that.
So Traversing deals with cycling through
elements,
going from the parent to the children,
from the children to the parent, or from a
sibling element to its sibling element.
So this is the place you wanna look if
you're doing anything Traversing related.
Now there's finally one place that I want
to take you to.
And that is Selectors.
So in Selectors you can see all this CSS
type
selectors that you would find from CSS one
through three.
And this is kind of really good to look
at, to
even discover some things that you may not
know about CSS.
Now there'll maybe some existing selectors
that you would want to
use when adding behavior but not
necessarily when adding a style.
So this is kind of a new resource to have
a look and it's also got very specific
jQuery selectors.
So, you can maybe use this in CSS files
but there's still a selector that jQuery
would recognize.
When coding jQuery, think about what
you're doing first.
Are you traversing or manipulating the
[UNKNOWN]?
Are you running events?
Once you've figured out what you're doing,
the documentation page won't seem as
daunting.