[MUSIC]
Have you ever wondered how to add that
additional functionality to the front
end of your website, that you just can't
do with HTML or CSS alone?
Such as custom navigations, tool tops,
form hints and animations based on events.
I'm Andrew, and welcome to jQuery basics.
Where I will show the basics of adding new
types of functionality to the front-end of
a website.
>> Throughout this course, we'll work on
several small projects to
bring up to speed on adding this behavior
to your sites.
jQuery basics is for people with a basic
grasp of java script.
Like creating variables, conditional
statements and functions.
If haven't had any of experience like this
already, you should probably check out one
of our other courses or projects that
covers the basics of java script and
programming.